Stephen W. Krewson

26 Edgewood Avenue, Unit 2, New Haven, CT 06511 (518) 928-3302 | stephen.krewson@yale.edu www.stephenkrewson.net

Education

2019	Ph.D. (expected). English. Yale University, New Haven, CT (YU).
2018	M.S. (expected). Computer Science. YU.
2015	M.A., M.Phil. English. YU.
2010	B.A. summa cum laude. English. Univ. of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA (UP).

Awards

2016	Developer Seed Grant (for collating illustrations across editions of children's books). DH Lab. YU.
2016	A. Bartlett Giamatti research fellowship. Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. YU.
2013 - 14	Fellow. Andrew Mellon Foundation, Interdisciplinary Humanities Seminar. YU.
2011-2013	Richard J. Franke Fellow. YU.
2010	Phi Beta Kappa. Dosoretz Prize (Best Undergraduate Essay, English). UP.
2009	College Alumni Society Poetry Prize (Richard Wilbur, judge). UP.
2007 – 2010	Benjamin Franklin Scholar. UP.

Teaching

2016	Teaching Fellow (TF). CPSC 201a: "Introduction to Computer Science." YU.
2015	TF. CPSC 100a: "Introduction to Computing and Programming." YU.
2015	Instructor. HUMS 304b: "The Grid: Data, History, Visualization." YU.
2014	TF. ENGL 201a: "Shakespeare: Histories and Tragedies." YU.
2011-12	GRE Instructor. Kaplan, Inc., Philadelphia, PA.

Work Experience

2016	Course Manager. Department of Computer Science. YU.
2015	Software Engineering Intern. ZEFR Inc., Venice, CA.
2009-11	Literacy Programming Coordinator. The Free Library, Philadelphia, PA.
2008-10	Marketing Assistant. Penn Press, Philadelphia, PA.
2008	Editorial Intern. McGraw-Hill Education, New York, NY.
2005-07	Assistant Account Manager. Merriam Insurance Agency, Schenectady, NY.

Research

2016 Individual presentation: "From 'Lame Jervas' to the African Free School: Educational Apparatus and Philanthropic Colonialism." Dartmouth Futures of American Studies Institute.

2016 Individual presentation: "The Generic Lyceum: Tracking a Social Movement by its Instruments." Digital workshop: "19C Lecture Topics: Synthesizing the Existing 'Databases'." C19: Biennial Conference of The Society of Nineteenth-Century Americanists. State College, PA.

2012–15 | Research Assistant. Profs. Caleb Smith and Michael Warner, New Haven, CT.

Arts and Letters

Languages | Reading knowledge of French, Latin, and Spanish.

Music "Fun with Music and Programming: Haskell, Euterpea, and LilyPond" (with Con-

nor Harris). CS50 Seminars 2015. Cambridge, MA.

Poetry | Published in Pennsylvania Gazette, Perigee, Mid-American Review.

Programming | C, Haskell, Python, and Ruby. Good working knowledge of Bash, CSS, Git,

HTML, LATEX, and PowerShell. Experience with AngularJS, D3.js, Jekyll, Flask,

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and Rails.

Readings | Yale Graduate Poets series (with CA Conrad), 2014.

Visual JPEG glitch art projection (Python). "Interactive Crown Street," Yale School of Architecture, 2014. Interactive poetry generator and projection (with Hans

Schoenburg) [Python, Arduino, Twitter API]. XS Storefront Collaborative, 2013.

About Me

Born in Palo Alto and raised in Schenectady, I'm writing a dissertation at Yale on the visual and epistemological culture of "educational media" in the 19C. Since Fall 2012 I have been taking interdisciplinary coursework in computing, sponsored in part by the Mellon Foundation. Next year I will be pursuing my master's degree in Yale's Computer Science department, where I manage the corps of teaching fellows for CPSC 201. I am an active member of the Americanist Colloquium, the Digital Humanities Working Group, and the Computer Graphics Group at Yale. Last spring, I co-designed and taught a seminar called "The Grid: Data, History, and Visualization." I captain an IM basketball team, enjoy making electronic music and riding bikes, and volunteer with Habitat for Humanity. My research interests are in antebellum literature, the history of science, information retrieval, and algorithmic writing.